{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Tinker","incorrectAnswers":["Tailor","Soldier","Spy"],"question":"What do you call a person who mends pots, kettles, and pans?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Niagara Falls","incorrectAnswers":["Grand Canyon","Great Barrier Reef","Mount Everest"],"question":"Which landmark is often viewed from Goat Island?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Motor racing","incorrectAnswers":["Hockey","Track and field","Table tennis"],"question":"With which sport is Michael Schumacher associated?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Here's Johnny!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Nobody puts Baby in a corner.\"","\"You’re going to go through life thinking that girls don’t like you because you’re a nerd. And I want you to know, from the bottom of my heart, that won’t be true. It’ll be because you’re an a**hole.\"","\"Yo, Adrian!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'The Shining'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Doors","incorrectAnswers":["Styx","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American rock band released the album 'Waiting for the Sun'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Doors","incorrectAnswers":["Styx","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American rock band released the song 'Riders on the Storm'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dog","incorrectAnswers":["Horse","Goat","Ghost"],"question":"The only __________ to ever appear in a Shakespearean play was Crab in \"The Two Gentlemen of Verona.\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"People's Republic of China","incorrectAnswers":["Bangladesh","Nepal","Myanmar"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Bhutan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1926","incorrectAnswers":["1899","1949","1866"],"question":"When did Roald Amundsen first reach the North Pole?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Persia","incorrectAnswers":["Greece","Rome","Egypt"],"question":"In the 480 B.C. Battle of Salamis, Athens joined other cities to defeat which nation?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Small thimbles","incorrectAnswers":["Elbows","Butterflies","Little ears"],"question":"The pasta ditalini has what meaning in Italian?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"A Driver Has Been Disqualified","incorrectAnswers":["The Race Has Been Won","A Driver Has Died","The Fastest Lap Has Been Set"],"question":"In Formula One what does it mean when they are waving a black flag?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Toronto FC","incorrectAnswers":["Toronto Bills","Toronto Predators","Toronto Canucks"],"question":"Which of these is a soccer team based in Toronto?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Aretha Franklin","incorrectAnswers":["Gladys Knight","Diana Ross","Patti LaBelle"],"question":"Which singer had a 1967 hit with \"You Make Me Feel Like A Natural Woman\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sphinx","incorrectAnswers":["Isis","Minos","Medusa"],"question":"In Greek mythology, the riddle of what did Oedipus solve?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The suspension system","incorrectAnswers":["The transmission system","The steering system","The braking system"],"question":"What is the term for the system in your car that includes the springs, dampers and other parts responsible for shock absorption?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Stringed","incorrectAnswers":["Percussion","Woodwind","Keyboard"],"question":"What type of instrument is a harp?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Neil Young","Eric Clapton"],"question":"Which musician released the song 'Beat It'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Margarita ","incorrectAnswers":["Martini","Bloody Mary","Tequila Sunrise"],"question":"What is the cocktail called, that consists of four parts of tequila to two parts of lemon or limejuice?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The Middle East","incorrectAnswers":["Central Asia","Africa","South America"],"question":"Where in the world is spinach originally from?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"To Kill a Mockingbird","incorrectAnswers":["Mad Max","Pirates of the Caribbean","Gone with the Wind"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Atticus Finch'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The Czech Republic","incorrectAnswers":["Austria","Poland","Germany"],"question":"What country is the largest consumer of beer per head?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Havana","incorrectAnswers":["San Salvador","Santiago","Guatemala City"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Cuba?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Room","incorrectAnswers":["L.A. Confidential","Barry Lyndon","Beauty and the Beast"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'Held captive for 7 years, a woman and her young son finally gain their freedom.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Twee","incorrectAnswers":["Dois","Deux","Één"],"question":"In Dutch, what is the word for for 'two'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Fort Knox","incorrectAnswers":["Fort Campbell","Fort Reginald","Fort Corid"],"question":"Where is most of America's gold located?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Taipei","incorrectAnswers":["Tarawa","Beijing","Apia"],"question":"What is the capital city of Taiwan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Doctor Zhivago","incorrectAnswers":["Catch-22","The Great Gatsby","Anna Karenina"],"question":"Which novel by Boris Pasternak, adapted into a film in 1965, tells the story of Yuri's passion for Lara amidst the backdrop of the Russian Revolution?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Sedimentary Rocks","incorrectAnswers":["Igneous Rocks","Metamorphic Rocks","Diamonds"],"question":"What type of rocks contain fossils?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Durian ","incorrectAnswers":["Mangosteen","Lychee","Dragonfruit"],"question":"Which Southeast Asian fruit is notorious for its putrid smell?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Canadian","incorrectAnswers":["American","English","Irish"],"question":"What Nationality Is Former Snooker World Champion Cliff Thorburn?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Daikon","incorrectAnswers":["Bok Choy","Soba","Miso"],"question":"Which of these is a type of Japanese radish?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Saudi Arabia","incorrectAnswers":["Burundi","Cuba","North Macedonia"],"question":"Riyadh is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Le Mans '66","incorrectAnswers":["Dr. Strangelove or: How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the Bomb","Ratatouille","Downfall"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A car designer and driver battle to build a revolutionary race car.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Barnacle","incorrectAnswers":["Clam","Oyster","Starfish"],"question":"What sea creature adheres firmly to rocks and to the bottom of ships?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Kebaya","incorrectAnswers":["Kaftan","Dashiki","Thobe"],"question":"Which of these is a form of clothing worn by women in Malaysia and Indonesia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Coca Cola","incorrectAnswers":["Gatorade","Dr. Pepper","Sunny Delight"],"question":"'It's the real thing' is a slogan associated with which drink brand?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Spanish","incorrectAnswers":["English","French","Portuguese"],"question":"What language is most widely spoken in Mexico?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ecuador","incorrectAnswers":["Tanzania","Brazil","Greece"],"question":"Which country owns the Galapagos Islands?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The g in 'green'","incorrectAnswers":["The v in 'village'","The r in 'red'","The m in 'mother'"],"question":"In phonetics, which of these is an example of a plosive sound?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Jamestown","incorrectAnswers":["St. Augustine","Plymouth","New Amsterdam"],"question":"What was the first permanent English settlement in America?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Montréal","incorrectAnswers":["Miami","Washington DC","Denver"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Canada?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Johnny Cash","incorrectAnswers":["Elvis Presley","Buddy Holly","Roy Orbison"],"question":"For which man is the album 'At San Quentin, More of Old Golden Throat' named?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Parmesan ","incorrectAnswers":["Wensleydale","Stilton","Gorgonzola"],"question":"What sort of cheese would you sprinkle on spaghetti?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Denmark","incorrectAnswers":["China","France","Greece"],"question":"Which country has the oldest national flag?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Brazil","incorrectAnswers":["Spain","Egypt","Argentina"],"question":"In which country would you find the city of Rio de Janeiro?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Indira Gandhi","incorrectAnswers":["Sonia Gandhi","Benazir Bhutto","Golda Meir"],"question":"Which female leader of India was killed by her bodyguards in 1984?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Wind in the Willows","incorrectAnswers":["Alice's Adventures in Wonderland","The Cat in the Hat","Charlotte's Web"],"question":"Which novel contains the line \"'Toad Hall,' said the Toad proudly, 'is an eligible self-contained gentleman's residence'\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Battle of Austerlitz","incorrectAnswers":["Battle of Talavera","Battle of Waterloo","Battle of Trafalgar"],"question":"Which battle did Napoleon win that proved his military genius?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Double Bass","incorrectAnswers":["Violin","Viola","Cello"],"question":"What is the lowest pitched stringed instrument?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Lady Gaga","incorrectAnswers":["Hikaru Utada","Drake","Madonna"],"question":"Which American singer, songwriter, and actress released the studio album 'Artpop'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"The stuff that dreams are made of.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Stella! Hey, Stella!\"","\"Nobody makes me bleed my own blood. Nobody!\"","\"I'll be back.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'The Maltese Falcon'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Verde","incorrectAnswers":["Vert","Groen","Rosso"],"question":"What is the Italian word for 'green'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Lisbon","incorrectAnswers":["Warsaw","Barcelona","Prague"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Portugal?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Treble","incorrectAnswers":["Soprano","Tenor","Alto"],"question":"According to a popular song by Meghan Trainor, you should be 'all about that bass...no' what?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Carnitas","incorrectAnswers":["Tacos","Burritos","Enchiladas"],"question":"What Mexican dish that means \"little meats\" is made with shredded pork?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Bloody Mary","incorrectAnswers":["Margarita","Sangria","Manhattan"],"question":"Which cocktail contains the following ingredients: Vodka, tomato juice, lemon, tabasco sauce, salt, pepper, celery, salt?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Cow","incorrectAnswers":["A Soar","A Worker","A Hen"],"question":"What is a female hippopotamus known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Gibraltar ","incorrectAnswers":["Valencia","Maroc","Moor"],"question":"Which Rock Is On The South Coast Of Spain?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"DOUX","incorrectAnswers":["TART","SVIN","POUT"],"question":"Which letters indicate that a French wine is sweet?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"An Owlet","incorrectAnswers":["A Caterpillar","A Codling","A Colt"],"question":"What would you call a baby owl?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The United Kingdom","incorrectAnswers":["France","The United States","Spain"],"question":"Bermuda is a part of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"El salvador","incorrectAnswers":["Honduras","Guatemala","Belize"],"question":"Name the only Central American country without an Atlantic coastline.","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Billingsgate","incorrectAnswers":["Ragamuffin","Pauciloquent","Collywobbles"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'coarsely abusive language'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Harry Potter","incorrectAnswers":["Sherlock Holmes","The Dark Tower","Twilight"],"question":"In which book series does 'Sirius Black' appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A loss leader","incorrectAnswers":["A bait","A customer trap","A clearance item"],"question":"What term is used to describe an item that's sold at retail for less than it cost wholesale as a way to lure customers?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1991","incorrectAnswers":["1983","1987","1995"],"question":"In which year was Beauty and the Beast released?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"It is used in manufacture of pulp and paper, alumina, soap and detergents.","incorrectAnswers":["It is used to relieve pain.","It is used as an ingredient in baking.","It is used in disinfectants and antiseptics."],"question":"What is the chemical sodium hydroxide often used for?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Wall Street Crash","incorrectAnswers":["The Hindenberg Disaster","The Assassination of John F. Kennedy","The Nazi Invasion of Poland"],"question":"What notorious event occurred on the 24th October 1929?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1968","incorrectAnswers":["1950","1956","1962"],"question":"In which year was 2001: A Space Odyssey released?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Shigeru Miyamoto","incorrectAnswers":["Yu Suzuki","Satoru Iwata","Gunpei Yokoi"],"question":"Which legendary games designer/producer created the Super Mario Brothers franchise for Nintendo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Blue","incorrectAnswers":["Yellow","Maroon","Gold"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Iceland?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"alternative method of massage, manipulative therapy|therapy or pressure on certain points of the sole of the feet as a means of relieving nervous tension","incorrectAnswers":["feces","study of the mouth and its diseases","karyotypes"],"question":"What is Reflexology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Oklahoma City Thunder","incorrectAnswers":["Oklahoma City Wizards","Oklahoma City Tigers","Oklahoma City FC"],"question":"Which of these is a basketball team based in Oklahoma City?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Brambles","incorrectAnswers":["Vaccines","Christianity","Pollen"],"question":"What is Batology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Mobile","incorrectAnswers":["Chandelier","Lampshade","Pendant"],"question":"What is a word refers to a decorative structure that can hang above a baby's crib?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Switzerland","incorrectAnswers":["Vietnam","Barbados","Ghana"],"question":"Rösti is a dish that is most associated with which part of the world?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Morocco","incorrectAnswers":["Egypt","Tunisia","Libya"],"question":"Which country is separated from Spain by the Strait of Gibraltar?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"John Lennon","incorrectAnswers":["John F Kennedy","Martin Luther King Jr","Harvey Milk"],"question":"Who was assassinated on December 8, 1980 in New York City?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Fifty Shades","incorrectAnswers":["Harry Potter","Twilight","Game of Thrones"],"question":"Which  words preceded 'Darker' and 'Freed' on two best selling books released in 2011 and 2012?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Heavy water","incorrectAnswers":["Dolomite","Cream of tartar","Hematite"],"question":"What is deuterium oxide commonly known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Philippines","incorrectAnswers":["Thailand","Bangladesh","Indonesia"],"question":"In which country is the city of Manila?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Tony Bennett","incorrectAnswers":["Dean Martin","Frank Sinatra","Nat King Cole"],"question":"Who sang 'I Left My Heart In San Francisco'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Hans Christian Andersen","incorrectAnswers":["Beatrix Potter","Søren Kierkegaard","Oscar Wilde"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Little Match Girl'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Namibia","incorrectAnswers":["Suriname","Mauritius","Bosnia and Herzegovina"],"question":"Windhoek is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Washington Nationals","incorrectAnswers":["Washington Saints","Washington Dolphins","Washington Bucks"],"question":"Which of these is a baseball team based in Washington?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The act done by me against my will is not my act","incorrectAnswers":["To act accidentally is not to act at all","Act as if you are always being watched","The act of an honest man cannot be questioned"],"question":"How does that Latin phrase 'Actus me invito factus non est meus actus' translate into English?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Alaska & Hawaii","incorrectAnswers":["Maine & New Hampshire","Vermont & Massachusetts","Rhode Island & Connecticut"],"question":"Which 2 US states share no land border with other states?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Trinidad and Tobago","incorrectAnswers":["Dominican Republic","Ecuador","Malta"],"question":"Port of Spain is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A consulate","incorrectAnswers":["An embargo","A missionary","A delegation"],"question":"What is the term for an office established by one country inside another to support and protect its citizens and aid commerce?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Agastopia","incorrectAnswers":["Dragoman","Oxter","Jentacular"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'admiration of a particular part of someone’s body'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Warlock","incorrectAnswers":["Mage","Magus","Magician"],"question":"What Is A Male Witch Known As","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Jack Nicklaus","incorrectAnswers":["Tiger Woods","Phil Mickelson","Bobby Jones"],"question":"Who was first to win the US Masters five times?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Bergamot ","incorrectAnswers":["Lavender","Lemon","Saffron"],"question":"Which ingredient gives Earl Grey tea its distinctive flavour?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Daniel Day-Lewis","incorrectAnswers":["Peter O'Toole","Sidney Poitier","Robert De Niro"],"question":"Which actor played the role of William 'Bill the Butcher' Cutting in Gangs of New York?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Belgium","incorrectAnswers":["France","Hungary","Denmark"],"question":"Brussels is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"New Zealand","incorrectAnswers":["Canada","United States","United Kingdom"],"question":"In which country is the city of Wellington?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Cycling","incorrectAnswers":["Skiing","Snooker","Tennis"],"question":"With which sport is Eddy Merckx associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Philip Reeve","incorrectAnswers":["Oscar Wilde","Robert Louis Stevenson","Christopher Tolkien"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Mortal Engines'?","difficulty":"hard"},